I'm going to give you over 10 years of web design knowledge in just 7 minutes.
我将用 7 分钟把我 10 多年的网页设计经验悉数传授给你。
No fluff, just the good stuff.
没有废话，都是干货。
Are you ready?
准备好了吗？
Let's go.
我们开始吧。
You can basically boil all the design knowledge that you need to build great websites down to just three things.
要打造出色的网站，所有设计知识其实可以归结为三件事。
Layout, color, and typography.
布局、配色和字体排版。
Probably heard it said before that people read or engage websites in somewhat of an F pattern.
你或许听过，人们浏览网页时会呈现一种“F 形”阅读模式。
So they start reading at the top left and then they go right, they come back, they go down on the left, they go right, they come back and they go down on the left until they're done.
也就是先从左上角开始向右看，再回到左侧往下扫，再向右看，如此往复，直到页面底部。
But here's the truth.
但真相是——
That's actually bogus.
这说法根本不靠谱。
It's outdated information that web designers just kind of keep repeating, and so everybody thinks it's true.
这是一条过时的“知识”，因为被设计师不断复述，大家才以为它正确。
I might have been one of those web designers, and for that I apologize.
我也曾是这样的人，为此向大家道歉。
The truth is, is that people engage with websites and all sorts of different patterns, and forcing them to pay attention in an F pattern might actually cause them to miss important information.
事实上，用户浏览网页的路径多种多样，硬让他们按 F 形去看，反而可能错过关键信息。
So what do you do instead?
那我们该怎么做呢？
You use something called visual hierarchy.
用“视觉层级”来引导视线。
Probably seen an image before where there's this big bold line of text that says you're going to read this first, and the smaller line underneath it that says then you'll read it next.
你肯定见过那种示意图：一行大而粗的文字告诉你“先看这里”，下面较小的文字表示“然后看这里”。
And then this really tiny line that's all the way in the left hand corner that says, and you'll read this last, that is visual hierarchy.
在左下角还有一行极小的字写着“最后看这里”，这就是视觉层级。
You make the most important elements of a section, the biggest and the boldest.
把最重要的元素做得又大又醒目。
And then for each other element that isn't maybe as important, you turn down the volume.
次要元素就“降低音量”，弱化它们的存在感。
You make it more inconspicuous for your call to action or buttons.
为了让行动号召或按钮突出，你要把其他元素做得更低调。
You want to make sure that they have a high degree of contrast from everything else around them.
你要确保这些按钮与周围元素有足够高的对比度。
Why?
为什么？
Because the main thing we want people to do on a website is click a button.
因为我们希望访客在网站上做的头号动作就是“点按钮”。
If it doesn't stand out, it's going to make it harder to do that.
按钮不醒目，点击率就会下降。
And please, I beg of you, stop using ghost buttons.
拜托拜托，别再用“幽灵按钮”了。
What are ghost buttons?
什么是幽灵按钮？
They're buttons that just have an outline without a solid background.
就是只有描边、没有实心背景的按钮。
The problem is that people don't see them and they don't click on them.
问题是用户根本看不到，更不会点。
For colors, every website should have a color palette that matches the brand of the website owner.
说到配色，每个网站都应有一套与品牌相符的色板。
Here's a few important things to consider when it comes to color.
下面是配色时要注意的几件大事。
The first thing is accessibility.
首先是可访问性。
If you pick colors that make it difficult to read text or tough to see elements clearly, it's going to be hard for users to engage.
如果颜色搭配让文字难读、元素难辨，用户体验就会很糟。
You want to pick colors that have a high enough contrast that even users with visual impairments are still going to be able to see things clearly.
色彩对比度要足够高，使视力受限的用户也能看清内容。
How do you know if a contrast is high enough?
如何判断对比度是否达标？
Something that I like using is a website calledcoolers.co.
我常用的网站是 coolers.co。
You could actually take all of the brand colors from a website and put it into the dashboard.
你可以把品牌的所有颜色输入它的面板。
Click on the color contrast teller and it will instantly tell you which colors pass and which super helpful tool.
点击“对比度检测”，它会立即告诉你哪些颜色通过、哪些不通过，超级好用。
Another good rule of thumb for colors is that you want to use a guideline called the 6030 ten rule.
另一个配色经验法则叫做“60‒30‒10 法则”。
Basically what this means is that about 60% of your website should use your dominant colors, things like Grays or blacks and whites.
意思是：大约 60% 的页面使用主色调，例如灰、黑或白。
30% you should reserve for your brand colors, and then another 10% you want to use something for an accent.
30% 用于品牌色，再拿 10% 来做强调色。
So helping things really stand out.
让重点元素真正跳出来。
That's a great thing to use for, like your calls to actions or your buttons.
这 10% 很适合用于行动号召或按钮。
Is this a hard and fast rule that you absolutely have to use every single time?
这是死规矩、次次都得照搬吗？
No, but it's a good principle to stick with, especially when you're first getting started.
当然不是，但尤其在新手阶段，这是很好的参考。
Then there's typography.
接下来讲字体排版。
Typography is one of the most underrated design elements of a website, but it has a massive impact on the readability and user experience.
字体排版常被忽视，却对可读性和体验影响巨大。
Thankfully, there's a ton of great options when it comes to fonts.
好在字体选择非常丰富。
You've got serifs, you've got sans serifs, you've got handwritten fonts, You've got scripts, you've got display, you've got monospace, and it goes on and on.
有衬线体、无衬线体、手写体、书法体、展示体、等宽体等等。
There are three main text elements to consider for your website.
网站上主要有三种文字元素需要关注。
You've got your H ones or your main headers, and this should be the biggest, most prominent text on the page.
首先是 H1，即主标题，应是页面最大、最醒目的文字。
This is going to describe what the entire page is all about.
它要概括整页内容。
Then you've got your H2 or your subheadings.
接着是 H2，也就是副标题。
These act as ways to divvy up the rest of the page and guide a user's attention.
用来分隔页面其他内容，引导用户视线。
Then finally you've got your paragraph text or your P tags.
最后是正文文字，也就是 P 标签。
You don't want to use really decorative text for this.
正文不要用太花哨的字体。
It might look cool, but it kills readability.
看起来酷，阅读体验却会崩。
But here's the thing.
话说回来。
Good design without good conversion practices doesn't actually help your clients.
只顾颜值而忽视转化，对客户毫无意义。
I designed a website a while back for a client and the result was way better than their old website.
之前我给客户做了个新站，外观比旧站强太多。
It was clean, it was modern, it was chef's kiss.
简洁、现代，完美到不行。
The problem was, when we launched it, sales plummeted.
结果上线后，销售额却断崖式下跌。
Why did that happen?
为什么会这样？
It's because I tried to make it look pretty instead of focusing on good conversion practice.
因为我只顾好看，没有聚焦转化。
If your design doesn't consider conversion, it's useless to your clients.
设计若不考虑转化，对客户就是零价值。
So what are good conversion practices?
那好的转化实践是什么？
Good conversion is all about reducing friction for users.
核心就是为用户“减阻”。
You want to make it stupid easy for the users to find what they're looking for and to go through and either buy a product or sign up for a service.
让他们轻松到“傻瓜式”地找到所需，完成购买或注册。
And that's done through clarity.
要做到这一点，必须“清晰”。
You want to be crystal clear about who the company is or the person is, who owns the website, and what the user is supposed to do next.
让用户一眼看明白：这是谁的网站，提供什么，并且下一步该做什么。
Why they should even You also do it through scan ability.
以及他们为什么要在意。此外，还要保证页面可“扫读”。
People aren't reading websites, they're scanning through it.
人们不是逐字阅读，而是扫视页面。
So you need to set things out in such a way that people can bounce around and make decisions.
因此布局要方便他们快速跳读并做决定。
And then finally, you want the website to be motivating.
最后，网站要具备“激励性”。
It's not just enough to be pretty.
仅靠颜值远远不够。
You actually need to speak to the heart of the user.
你得打动用户的内心。
Speak to the thing that's driving them to say yes or no.
触及促使他们下决定的那根“动因”。
But overall, you want to design for the right audience, not for yourself and not for your client.
总之，设计要面向目标受众，而非你自己，也非你的客户。
It doesn't matter if you love the design.
你喜欢不喜欢，没那么重要。
It doesn't even matter if your client loves the design.
甚至客户喜欢不喜欢，都不是关键。
Who does it matter for?
关键是谁？
The website visitors.
网站访客。
So do a little research.
所以先做些调研。
Who's actually using this website.
弄清真正的使用者是谁。
Fonts, colors, layout.
字体、颜色、布局——
Choose them based on the target audience and not personal preference.
都要根据受众而非个人喜好来定。
Finally, make sure that you never stop learning.
最后一点：永远别停止学习。
Web designers don't age like fine wine, OK?
网页设计师可不是陈年美酒，
We age like a loaf of bread left on the counter.
更像放在台面上的面包。
We go stale unless we keep learning.
不学习就发霉走味。
The web design industry is changing fast, and it's going to continue to do so.
行业变化飞快，而且只会越来越快。
What worked just five years ago might not work today.
五年前奏效的方法，今天可能就失灵。
It might not work in the next five years.
未来五年更不一定管用。
And if you don't challenge yourself and stay updated, you're going to fall behind.
不主动挑战自我、保持更新，很快就会被甩开。
Will AI take all of our jobs?
AI 会抢走我们所有的饭碗吗？
Probably not.
大概率不会。
But will AI take lazy web designer jobs?
但 AI 会抢走那些偷懒设计师的饭碗吗？
Absolutely.
绝对会。
The only way to stay valuable is to keep learning, keep adjusting, and keep leveling up.
想保持价值，就得持续学习、不断调整、不断升级。
And you might be asking yourself, that's all well and good, but what do I need to do if I'm getting started today?
你可能会问：听着都不错，可如果我今天才入行，该怎么做？
Thankfully, I've got another video that I'm going to link to that's going to answer just those questions.
不用担心，我有一支视频专门回答这些问题，链接放在下面。
Make sure that you like this video if it was helpful, and be sure to subscribe so that you don't miss another episode.
如果这支视频对你有帮助，请点个赞并订阅频道，别错过后续内容。
And don't forget, if you don't quit, you win.
记住：只要不放弃，你就会成功。